<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
      <feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <title>Deep Geo Devlog</title>
        <link href="http://deengames-prototypes.github.io/deep-geo" />
        <id>urn:uuid:83ade4416d08024891d78f55ed986679</id>
  	    <updated>2017-02-24T00:00:00Z</updated><entry>
      		<title>Week 1: Prototyping Puzzles</title>
          <link href="http://deengames-prototypes.github.io/deep-geo/week-1-prototyping-puzzles" />
      		<id>urn:uuid:89e3cf227dfc22bca628ff354a3f9b75</id>
      		<updated>2017-02-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
      		<summary>Week 1: Prototyping Puzzles</summary>
      		<content type="xhtml">
      			&lt;p&gt;A wanted to create a non-combat-focused roguelike with Deep Geo. This necessitates interersting, non-combat mechanics. I settled on three ideas; this week, I implemented two ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Push/Pull Block Puzzles&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inspired by Lufia 2, 30% of floors generate a push/pull puzzle. Six barrels appear on the floor (three red and three blue), and six receptacles where you have to place a barrel of the matching colour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can push the blocks, and also pull them by holding space and moving:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="content/images/gifs/week-1-barrels.gif" alt="pushing and pulling blocks" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Placing all six barrels on matching receptacles solves the puzzle and nets three keys. Which brings us to the next idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Locked Doors and keys&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Few roguelikes use the concept of key-locked doors. While this is hard to generate meaningfully (how can I guarantee that you need to get keys to lock doors? How can I make sure this is solvable and keys are not behind locked doors?), one advantage of roguelikes is that you can always go back up a floor and come back down to generate a new floor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keys are pretty simple: any key can unlock any locked door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="content/images/gifs/week-1-keys.gif" alt="keys and doors" /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next week, I plan to implement the third feature (switch puzzles which simultaneously activate multiple doors). If that goes well, I can add monsters, and see if/how the puzzles work with actual monsters hounding you.&lt;/p&gt;
      		</content>
      		<author>
      			<name>ashes999</name>
      			<email>ashes999@yahoo.com</email>
      		</author>
      	</entry>
      	<entry>
      		<title>Week 0: Planning</title>
          <link href="http://deengames-prototypes.github.io/deep-geo/week-0-planning" />
      		<id>urn:uuid:870602053a67d206658a7ca3e0bc021a</id>
      		<updated>2017-02-17T00:00:00Z</updated>
      		<summary>Week 0: Planning</summary>
      		<content type="xhtml">
      			&lt;p&gt;This week, I completed planning for a new ASCII non-combat roguelike themed around nuclear risk. The working game title is Deep Geo (a short-form of Deep Geological Repository).  You can read more about nuclear risk and why it matters, nuclear waste, etc. with the following links (which I took as insipration for my game design and goals):&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.gamesforchange.org/2016/11/why-were-getting-serious-about-nuclear-weapons-with-epic-orphan"&gt;Games for Change: Why Nuclear Weapons Matter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Radioactive_waste"&gt;Wikipedia: Radioactive Waste&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Deep_geological_repository"&gt;Wikipedia: Deep Geological Repository&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Waste_Isolation_Pilot_Plant"&gt;Wikipedia: Waste Isolation Pilot Plant&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week, I nailed down the theme and core gameplay; it consists of:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Stealth mechanics (monsters have a field of view, and you need to stay out of it; patience while cloaked to avoid encounters)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Non-tradiitional (escape/flee) combat style. There's no damage inflicted, but you can stun, sprint for a short time, push enemies, and cloak yourself (if you don't move).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Puzzles. These may be switch puzzles (several switches operate several doors simultaneously), push-stuff-around puzzles, keys and locked doors, and items/parts you have to combine/use.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there are some important, unanswered questions (how do you complete puzzles with  monsters breathing down your neck? Do we have experience and levelling up?), it's ready enough to start working on. So I'll start working on it this week or early next week.&lt;/p&gt;
      		</content>
      		<author>
      			<name>ashes999</name>
      			<email>ashes999@yahoo.com</email>
      		</author>
      	</entry>
      	</feed>